A Finding Aid to the Baxter Art Gallery Records, 1968-1990, in the Archives of American Art AAA.baxtart
Archives of American Art
- Printed Material, 1971-1987; Series 5; 0.5 Linear feet Box 14, OV 16
  - American Federation of Arts Film Programs, 1975-1982 (Box 14, Folder 6-7)
  - "California Institute of Technology Campus Development Planning Report", 1979 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Exhibition and Event Flyers, 1980s (Box 14, Folder 9-10)
  - News Clippings, 1973-1985 (Box 14, Folder 11-12)
  - Publications Regarding Film Collections, 1979-1981 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Publications from Other Museums, circa 1973-1987 (Box 14, Folder 14-16)
  - Posters, 1971-1986 (Box OV 16)
- Pasadena Gallery of Contemporary Arts Records, 1981-1987; Series 6; 1.3 Linear feet Boxes 14-15
  Contained here are the records of the Pasadena Gallery of Contemporary Arts, founded by Jay Belloli as a replacement for the Baxter Art Gallery. Much of the documentation concerns the design of the Armory Center for the Visual Arts, the building which would include an exhibition space for the Pasadena Gallery of Contemporary Arts. Included are feasibility studies, steering committee documents, leases, and photographs. There are also Board of Director and Trustees documents which discuss the founding of the new gallery and meeting agendas and minutes. General planning records for the gallery include correspondence, meeting notes, press materials, and memos.
  - Architects, 1985-1986 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Armory Center for the Visual Arts (Box 14)
    - Active Spaceplan, circa 1986-1987 (Box 14, Folder 18-19)
    - Campaign Steering Committee, 1985-1986 (Box 14, Folder 20-23)
    - Joint Venture, 1985-1986 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Lease, 1985-1986 (Box 14, Folder 25-27)
    - Memorial Park, 1985-1986 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Photographs of Armory, circa 1985 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Presentation File, 1985-1986 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Board of Trustees/Board of Directors, 1985-1986 (Box 14, Folder 31-32)
  - Education Program Planning, 1981-1986 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Feasibility Study, 1983-1985 (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
  - Financial Records, 1984-1986 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Harrison Price Company, 1983-1985 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Kresge Foundation, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - "Market and Financial Feasibility for a Proposed Contemporary Art Museum in Pasadena", 1985 (Box 15, Folder 6-7)
  - Museum of Contemporary Art Los Angeles - "Proposal for a Strategic Development Plan", 1983 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - New Museum - General Planning, circa 1983-1987 (Box 15, Folder 9-16)
  - Pasadena Area Cultural Institutions Consortium, 1985-1986 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Pasadena Art Workshops, 1983-1986 (Box 15, Folder 18-19)
  - Pasadena Centennial Art Competition, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Publicity, 1985-1986 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Stationery Design, circa 1986 (Box 15, Folder 22)
- Motion Picture Film, circa 1970; circa 1975; Series 7; 3 Folders Box 15
  Found here are three films (16mm) by artist Lillian Schwartz. “Pixillation” includes Ken Knowlton as co-creator in the film credits. It is very likely that these films were shown as part of a film festival or screening at Baxter Art Gallery.
  - "Pixillation" by Lillian Schwartz and Ken Knowlton, circa 1970; 1 Film reels (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - "Collage" by Lillian Schwartz, circa 1975; 1 Film reels (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - "Alae" by Lillian Schwartz, circa 1975; 1 Film reels (Box 15, Folder 25)